# Ali Abharya

#### Python Backend Developer

I am a practical software developer with 4 years of experience in delivering Pythonic solutions for various web development tasks including REST and grpc API implementation, database guery optimization and effectively unit testing business services. As an open source developer I actively maintain two django packages named django-persian-pdf and django-cache-pydantic.



→ abharva.dev@gmail.com



+98 912 431 8673



Tehran, Iran



github.com/BinDruid

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Backend Developer** Rayan Bourse

2023 - Present

- Completely re-write a C# based invoice manager system using Djagno, Adding new switchable features including: 1) Event Driven notification service, 2) Workflow definition service with template pattern and protocols, 3) Monthly report generation service via grpc, 4) Seamless user interaction using htmx, 5) User registration and authorization with SSO and 6) Logging aggregation with Kafka.
- Engaged in code reviews and helped team members to reach higher level code quality using a selection of linting rules and tools with a combination of pre-commit and Ruff in local development and integrating Sonar Qube and Bandit security analysis in CI/CD pipeline.
- Unit testing and refactoring legacy code bases. Fixing issues regarding slow queries or N+1 queries in the meantime.
- Maintaining and co-committing internal pythonic packages for model validations and third-party API calls.

## **Backend Developer**

#### Asmari Insurance

2022 - 2023

- Creating a web socket notification service using Django Channels and Django REST Framework. Enabling admin users to send live notifications to groups of user. Also scheduled offline notifications were orchestrated as Celery task through the same service.
- Refactoring authorization system by introducing an abstract permissions class using the Strategy pattern, reducing codebase and streamlining the process of adding new permissions.
- Reorganizing business functionalities through the conversion of numerous external SOAP / REST API calls through the utilization of the Command Pattern.
- Breaking down a template-based financial report system into two services, using both DRF and Vue. These changes coupled with query optimization, yielded a tangible boost in the system's response time.

#### Fullstack Developer Ofogh Fannavar Noura

2020 - 2021

 Developed a data analysis dashboard using Django REST Framework, psycopg2, pandas, VUE 3, Vutify and APEX chart similar to Power BI dashboard including functionalities such as cross-filter and drill through. Effectively allowing business domain experts to be able to extract financial insights by interacting with dynamic charts.

#### TECHNOLOGY STACK



### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Django Persian PDF

Django Cache Pydantic

Twitter Fast API Clone

Spotify Gin API Clone

Oracle Postgres Migration CLI

Twitch Chat Moderation Bot

## **EDUCATION**

FUM(Ferdowsi University of Mashhad) (2010 - 2015)

B.S. In Computer Engineering

## **ARTICLES**

JDL Fusion Model for ECG Arrhythmia Detection, A Statistical Classifier (12/2012) INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF SIGNAL PROCESSING. IMAGE PROCESSING AND PATTERN RECOGNITION